BISMI ALLAH AL-RAHMAN AL-RAHIM. In the name of God, Most Gracious, Most Merciful.
Brothers and sisters AL-Salãmu ‘Alaykum. The Friday congregational prayer is an
obligatory duty upon every Muslim man and woman. This is a social function
decreed by God Almighty for the Muslims to get together and to know each other
and to be familiar with their problems and their joys. And we find in SURA
number 62 verse number 9, the commandment from God says o you who believe when the
contact prayers, the SALAT for Friday, is announced, you shall go to the mosque and
observe the SALAT prayer, and drop all business. This is better for
you if you only knew. So, if anyone is afraid that he or she may lose some
business during the Friday prayer, God is saying this should be better for you
God will make it up to you. God runs the world and He is the only
provider and He guarantees you doing better if you go to the Friday prayer.
And notice that the commandment said o you who believe.
It didn't say o you believing men or o you believing women. It says o you who
believe when the contact prayer on Friday is called for, you shall go and
drop all business. It is very important. I'm emphasizing the role of the women
because this is also an educational meeting where people sit down and
listen to a sermon and the Muslim woman must be the best educated because she
teaches the children. Women are our mothers and they teach
us as we grow up and it is essential that they are educated, not ignorant.
The traditional customary Muslims of the Middle East, they kept the women away
from the mosque and this kept the children ignorant because the mothers
are ignorant as far as the religion is concerned. So, it is very important to
emphasize this fact that Muslim men and women are required. It is an obligatory
duty for them to go to the Friday prayer.
Now, there are certain conditions for the Friday prayer. The people dress nicely as
commanded in the Quran, and they go for the noon prayer on Friday to the mosque.
And the Imam or the person who gives the sermon is required to follow certain
traditions. These are religious traditions or duties that came to us all
the way from Abraham and it is universal. This is the way it is happening all over the world.
The first condition is that throughout
the prayer from the beginning to the end, you mention only the name of God, ALLAH
SUBHANAHU WA TA'ALA in the AZAN. The AZAN should be ALLAH-O AKBAR, ALLAH-O AKBAR
ALLAH-O AKBAR, ALLAH-O AKBAR, La Elaha Ella Allah. This is the AZAN.
Now, the AZAN should be ALLAH-O AKBAR, ALLAH-O AKBAR
ALLAH-O AKBAR, ALLAH-O AKBAR, La Elaha Ella Allah. This is the AZAN. So, the AZAN or the call for
contact prayer is delivered. Then, the Imam stands up in front of the
congregation and he starts the first sermon by saying ALHAMDU LILLAH.
This is the first requirement. Now, you notice I said the first sermon,
because the KHUTBA or sermon on Friday consists of two sections or two sermons.
The prayer itself consists of two RAKATs, instead of four. The customary noon prayer
consists of four RAKATs or four units but on Friday, it is only two
RAKATs or two units and this is because the two sermons compensate for two
RAKATs or two units. So, the first sermon and also the second sermon, they must
begin by stating ALHAMDU LILLAH, praise be to God, followed by the SHAHADA.
And the SHAHADA, as dictated in the Quran, in SURA number 3 verse 81, the SHAHADA is
La Elaha Ella Allah. That's it. So, the Imam stands up and he begins
each sermon the first one and the second one by saying ALHAMDU LILLAH. La Elaha Ella Allah.
Then, he goes into the sermon, the subject in any language that he wishes.
Of course, in this country in the united states, it'll be English,
so the people will understand. If the Imam, during the sermon, uses Quran in Arabic,
he must translate it, so the people will understand. This is the whole idea of a sermon.
The sermon also deals with the local conditions of the local community.
Or it can deal with a general lesson from the Quran or a general religious lesson.
So, let me write for you the first requirement
which is stating ALHAMDU LILLAH. La Elaha Ella Allah. at the beginning of each sermon.
The Imam stands up for the sermon and the first thing he
says in the first sermon and the second sermon is ALHAMDU LILLAH. This is how it looks in writing.
AL-Hamdu Lillah,
which means praise be to God.
La Elaha Ella Allah, which looks like this. La means no.
Elaha means god with a small g.
La Elaha Ella, except
Ella Allah.
La Elaha Ella Allah. There is no god except Allah.
This is the required utterance at the beginning of the first sermon and the
second sermon. After this, you go into the subject of your sermon. Now, you notice
I didn't say anything else. This is what you start with. ALHAMDU LILLAH. La Elaha Ella Allah.
You don't start with BISMI ALLAH AL-RAHMAN AL-RAHIM, or dear
brothers and sisters or AL-Salãmu ‘Alaykum or anything else.
The minute you stand up for the sermon, you say ALHAMDU LILLAH. La Elaha Ella Allah.
Then, you can say dear brothers and sisters, AL-Salãmu ‘Alaykum. I want to talk
to you today about the contact prayers, the SALAT, for example, or whatever your subject is.
After you finish the subject of the first sermon, how do you finish the first sermon?
You finish it by asking the people to repent. You can ask them in
Arabic and then translate it to English. And the Arabic is Tooboo Ela Allah. Repent.
This is how you end the first sermon. Let me write it for you.
Tooboo means repent, plural.
Ela Allah.
Tooboo Ela Allah. And this is how you end the first sermon.
Now, as soon as you say Tooboo Ela Allah. Repent,
you sit down and you repent yourself. You sit down and you pray to
God please, God forgive me. I repent to you. I will never commit a sin after
after now, and you mean it.
Now, as soon as you say Tooboo Ela Allah to end the first sermon,
you sit down yourself and you repent. You ask God to forgive you.
So, here's how you end the first sermon.
You finish your subject, then you say to the people Tooboo Ela Allah. Repent.
And then you sit down
and you ask God to forgive you and you declare your repentance.
You say please, God forgive me. I repent. I will never commit a sin after now. And you
mean it. Of course, you're gonna fall in sin again, but God says He loves those
who continuously repent. So, you sit down for about a minute, no more, just one minute.
And everybody in the mosque will be asking God for forgiveness.
And everyone at the mosque will be repenting, and then you stand up for the
second sermon. And you start the second sermon by - that's right - ALHAMDU LILLAH.
La Elaha Ella Allah. This is how you start the second sermon
exactly the same way as the first sermon. Then, you either continue the subject you were
talking about in the first sermon, or you talk about a new subject. You can have
two different subjects for the two sermons. And after you finish talking in
the second sermon, you end this last sermon by saying
Aqem Al-Salah. And this is a sign to someone in the congregation to declare
that the SALAT, the contact prayer for Friday, is ready to be observed and
everybody stands up.
You end the sermon by saying Aqem Al-Salah. Let me write it for you.
Aqem
Al-Salah
Aqem Al-Salah
Now, the minute you say Aqem Al-Salah, the second sermon is over,
and a person in the congregation will say ALLAH-O AKBAR, ALLAH-O AKBAR
ALLAH-O AKBAR, ALLAH-O AKBAR, La Elaha Ella Allah. And this means everybody stand
up and let us pray. Then, as the Imam who gave the two
sermons, you stand up in front of the congregation and you pray two RAKATs as usual.
And I'm going to show you now an example of Friday congregation sermons.
God bless you.
So, let me summarize for you. You begin the first sermon by saying ALHAMDU LILLAH.
La Elaha Ella Allah. Then, you go into your subject in English. Then, you end the
first sermon by saying Tooboo Ela Allah. Then, you sit down and you ask God for
forgiveness and you repent. You sit down for about one minute, no more than that.
Then, you stand up and you start the second sermon by saying the same thing
ALHAMDU LILLAH. La Elaha Ella Allah. Then, you go into your subject that you want
to talk about and you end the second sermon by saying Aqem Al-Salah.
When you say that, someone in the congregation that knows that he was
going to do this, will stand up and say ALLAH-O AKBAR, ALLAH-O AKBAR,
ALLAH-O AKBAR, ALLAH-O AKBAR, La Elaha Ella Allah. And then, everyone in the mosque stands up and
they line... they stand up in straight lines behind you, the Imam. You take your
place and you do the Friday prayer exactly like the morning prayer. It is
identical to the morning prayer because it consists of only two RAKATs, or two units.
Now, the exact method of doing the SALAT, the contact prayers, is explained
in our tape entitled principles of Muslim prayer.
This gives the details of all five daily contact prayers.
ALHAMDU LILLAH, WA ASHHADU AN LA ILAHA ILLA ALLAH, WAHDAHU LA SHARIKA LAH.
Praise be to God and we bear witness that there's only one God.
I want to start my KHUTBA this time with the beautiful quotation
from the Bible from Luke 12:29 to 31. It is, of course, a Quranic idea. The
author is one and the same. And this is expressed beautifully in English.
Starting at 29, it says it is not for you
to be in search of what you are to eat or drink. Stop worrying.
The unbelievers of this world are always running after these things.
God knows that you need such things. Seek out, instead, His kingship over you
and the rest will follow in turn. So, all you need to do is seek
God's kingship over you and everything else you need follows, the food, the
provisions, the clothing, the health, everything else follows.
So, what does this mean? What does seeking God's Kingship mean?
It means that you give priority to God's commandments. You give priority to the
five contact prayers. You wake up in the morning and you say my duty today is to
do the five contact prayers.
That you... the Friday prayer is a commandment from God. There is a
commandment in Sura 60, verse 9, that you must go to the Friday prayer. You give this priority.
You arrange your life and your job and your circumstances,
so you will do the five daily prayers and the Friday prayer.
And of course, you people here are the least people who need this. Some people
out there are the ones who need this kind of reminder.
You put on the list of your priorities the Quranic study. There's a Quranic
study every Friday night going on here, where we study the Word of God.
And you have to work your circumstances. You cannot be somewhere in Tucson and there's
a Quranic study going on in the mosque.
Otherwise, you don't really care. You're not seeking God's Kinship over you. To be
sitting within say 50 miles and there's a Quranic study going on.
What does it mean to seek God's kinship over you and everything else follows, the
provisions, the health, the happiness? You give priority to the activities
of the believers. You remember the verse in SURA 18 that says force yourself
to be with those who worship God alone, because it takes some effort and some
work. It's not easy but this is what is good for you, as you'll see in the
second KHUTBA, IN SHAA ALLAH.
It means that you make a point of giving out the ZAKAT. charity, as
commanded by God. This is how you seek God's Kingship over you.
One day in the year, whatever January 1st, December 31st, the first day of Ramadan,
any day you set for yourself, one day in the year. You calculate exactly how
much you are worth and you give out two and a half percent to people that you
know, personally, people who need your charity. And the Quran gives the exact
order, your parents first. If they don't need it, then your relatives, your cousins
your brothers, sisters. I mean, your genetic brothers and sisters. And if all
your relatives are rich, they don't need it, then you go to the orphans, children
who have no support, one of the parents is missing somehow.
And after that the traveling stranger, somebody stranded from Mexico or
Nicaragua or whatever and passes by your house or you know personally, people who
immigrated from Thailand or Vietnam and they're living in a house in a terrible
conditions and you know them. Then, they come next. So, there is a specific
sequence or order to give out this charity.
You give priority to HAJJ, eventually, not now. I wouldn't advise you to
do it now. The Quran makes it conditional. Someday all of us, IN SHAA ALLAH, we'll go.
We're gonna charter a plane when we'll go all of us. We'll make HAJJ and we'll go
in as there will be great victory, because the land over there will be
worshiping God alone. This is God's promise to us and
therefore I can talk about it in this way. So eventually, you have to observe HAJJ.
You seek God's Kingship over you and everything else follows by observing the
prohibitions that God gave you. You don't drink. You don't gamble.
You don't eat pork. You don't lie. You don't cheat. You don't
violate your promises. You must be a person of your word.
You must be an example of a person of God, one a member in God's Kingdom.
Anything else in your life must take place number two. You give priority to
these activities, the commands of God, and this way you seek God's Kingship over you
and this way, you attain all other goals: money, health, wealth,
happiness et cetera, et cetera. Tooboo Ela Allah. Repent.
ALHAMDU LILLAH, WA ASHHADU AN LA ILAHA ILLA ALLAH, WAHDAHU LA SHARIKA LAH.
By studying the Quran continuously, we have discovered the secret of happiness.
The secret of happiness is a developed, nourished and growing soul, the real you,
the real person, not this body. This is the secret of happiness and we
came to this conclusion by studying people who obtained everything. They got
everything that the human beings go after: money, fame, good looks, sports cars,
whatever. And I have used the example of Eddie Murphy, a movie star, when he was
interviewed by Barbara Walters. He's got millions of dollars. He got palaces in
California exclusive places and in New Jersey, five luxurious cars, all the
girls, all the money, all the fame that he wants, and he told Barbara Walters he was
not happy. So, what is the secret of... Aren't these the things that people are
going after, money and fame and wealth and whatever? And he's not happy. So, the
secret of happiness is that he must develop his soul and the soul can be
developed by worshiping God alone.
Now this KHUTBA,
I want to talk about God's name: AL-RAZAQ, the provider, the provider. God is
the exclusive provider. He's the one who decides how much money
you're going to make or you made from birth to death.
And I want to shed a whole new light on this word: the provider, because God
provides for the body and for the soul.
Therefore, the contact prayers that you do five times a day are a provision from God.
The duties that I talked about in the first KHUTBA,
they're actually a gift from God. And we see this... there's a lot of
evidence in the Quran for this.
For example, in SURA 7 verse 43, we see that the people in Heaven pray and say
ALHAMDU LILLAH, praise be to God who guided us to this. We could not... we could
never be guided without God's blessing and guiding us. In other words, it was not their
doing. It is God's blessing and God's gift to them that guided them.
In SURA 10 verse 9, we see a very clear principle saying that God guides the
people because of their faith, or their belief. In other words, when you decide to
worship God alone, then God provides for your soul.
And God provides the five contact prayers for your soul and the fasting of
the month of Ramadan for your soul. I mean, you think that you're gonna do
the five prayers, but really it's a gift from God. You cannot do it without God's
guidance, SURA 9 verse 10.... SURA 10 verse 9, excuse me.
In SURA 49 verse 17, another clear evidence for this. The verse says
they act as if they are doing you a favor by embracing Islam or by
practicing Islam. Instead, God is the one who blessed them
by guiding them to Islam. So, when we worship God alone, when we do the five
daily prayers, when we fast the month of Ramadan, when we join the Quranic
study, and even the picnics of the Muslim group,
we are not doing God a favor. It is God's provisions to our souls.
In SURA 14 verse 40, we see Abraham praying, and what is he saying? He says
please, God make me an observable of the contact prayers,
because it's a gift from God - and also my children he said. He said
please God make me an observer of the contact prayers. رَبِّ ٱجْعَلْنِى مُقِيمَ ٱلصَّلَوٰةِ (14:40) in Arabic.
He didn't say please God give me a million dollars.
So, observing the five contact prayers is a privilege and a gift and a
blessing. It is not a hardship. It is not work. You get up for the morning prayer
before sunrise not because you want to do this or because you're doing such a
great effort, you know, for God's sake, it's because God blessed you and enabled
you to get up before sunrise to feed your soul, this very important meal the
morning prayer.
Abraham said رَبِّ ٱجْعَلْنِى مُقِيمَ ٱلصَّلَوٰةِ (14:40) My lord make me one who observes the
contact prayers, and also my children.
People in Satan's Kingdom are provided with sins.
We see this in SURA of 24 verse 21, when Satan collects people in his
kingdom, he pushes them to go to the bar, and lie, and cheat, and drink, and do not
feed your soul. This is what sins are, not feeding the
soul, depriving the soul, poverty of the soul.
On the other hand, in SURA 7 verse 28, we see the principle that God does not
advocate vice.
So, it's the exact opposite of what Satan does.
And this is why I want to remind you again that God never ordered Abraham to
slaughter his son, because this is a terrible vice, of course. And this is why we
never never find it in the Quran that Abraham ordered Abraham to sacrifice
his son. That wouldn't make sense, and it does not... this law that God does not
advocate sins would be violated.
People in Satan's kingdom, because of their idol worship,
they may observe the five contact prayers,
but they do not make contact. They dial the wrong number.
They dial Satan's number, because they mention other names with God. And this is
a trick of Satan. And this is why we find in the Quran such statements as woe to
those who observe the SALAT prayers. وَيْلٌ لِلْمُصَلِّينَ (107:4)
Because now they are really doing an effort,
but it's all in vain, as we see in SURA 39. It is all in vain. Once there's a name
mentioned with God in the prayer, it violates the commandment in SURA 72 verse 18.
Once another name is mentioned, the whole
effort is in vain. And we are blessed here. See, we're gonna
stand up. We're gonna pray to God. We're gonna establish contact
with God and there will be no name from the moment we say Allah Akbar to open
the prayer, to the end, there'll be no name but the name of God.
And you can see the difference.
Aqem Al-Salah
ALLAH-O AKBAR, ALLAH-O AKBAR, LA ILAAHA ILLAA ALLAH.
ALLAH-O AKBAR
(1:1) بِسْمِ ٱللَّهِ ٱلرَّحْمَـٰنِ ٱلرَّحِيمِ
(1:2) ٱلْحَمْدُ لِلَّهِ رَبِّ ٱلْعَـٰلَمِينَ
(1:3) ٱلرَّحْمَـٰنِ ٱلرَّحِيمِ (1:4) مَـٰلِكِ يَوْمِ ٱلدِّينِ (1:5) إِيَّاكَ نَعْبُدُ وَإِيَّاكَ نَسْتَعِينُ
(1:6) ٱهْدِنَا ٱلصِّرَٰطَ ٱلْمُسْتَقِيمَ (1:7) صِرَٰطَ ٱلَّذِينَ أَنْعَمْتَ عَلَيْهِمْ غَيْرِ ٱلْمَغْضُوبِ عَلَيْهِمْ وَلَا ٱلضَّآلِّينَ
ALLAH-O AKBAR
سمع الله لمن حمده (God listens to those who say praise) ALLAH-O AKBAR (God is the greatest)
ALLAH-O AKBAR (God is the greatest) ALLAH-O AKBAR (God is the greatest)
ALLAAH AKBAR (God is the greatest)
(1:1) بِسْمِ ٱللَّهِ ٱلرَّحْمَـٰنِ ٱلرَّحِيمِ (1:2) ٱلْحَمْدُ لِلَّهِ رَبِّ ٱلْعَـٰلَمِينَ (1:3) ٱلرَّحْمَـٰنِ ٱلرَّحِيمِ
(1:4) مَـٰلِكِ يَوْمِ ٱلدِّينِ (1:5) إِيَّاكَ نَعْبُدُ وَإِيَّاكَ نَسْتَعِينُ
(1:6) ٱهْدِنَا ٱلصِّرَٰطَ ٱلْمُسْتَقِيمَ (1:7) صِرَٰطَ ٱلَّذِينَ أَنْعَمْتَ عَلَيْهِمْ غَيْرِ ٱلْمَغْضُوبِ عَلَيْهِمْ وَلَا ٱلضَّآلِّينَ
ALLAH-O AKBAR (God is the greatest)
سمع الله لمن حمده (God listens to those who say praise) ALLAH-O AKBAR (God is the greatest)
ALLAH-O AKBAR (God is the greatest) ALLAH-O AKBAR (God is the greatest)
ALLAH-O AKBAR (God is the greatest)
ASALAAMU ALAYKUM (peace be upon you) ASALAAMU ALAYKUM (peace be upon you)
This is why it is appropriate to say
congratulations at the end of the prayer, because you just received a gift
from God, the equivalent of a hundred million dollars in your account.
Congratulations.
ALHAMDULILLAH, praise be to God
WA ASHADU AN LA ILLHA ILLA ALLAH WAHDAHU LA SHARIKA LAH.
And I bear witness there's no god except the One God.
Our topic today is a very important one, marriage in Islam.
God has prescribed for us laws to govern the important aspects of
our lives and He left a lot of freedom for many other aspects in our lives.
And we're told that these laws are recommendations or commandments.
They are commandments because we should do them
and they are recommendations because we have the freedom not to do them, as long
as we are ready to pay the price.
God tells us in SURA 10 verse 62 that if you follow these commandments, you are
guaranteed happiness, perfect happiness in this world.
And tells us in SURA 21 verse 142 that if you disregard these commandments, you
are guaranteed a miserable life.
So, it is very important for us to know these laws with regard to every aspect of
our lives, and today I'm going to share with you the commandments dealing with
marriage.
There are two requirements that must be fulfilled
for two people to get married. And these are... Number one is love.
And we see this in SURA 4 verse 24. The Arabic is فَمَا ٱسْتَمْتَعْتُم بِهِۦ مِنْهُنَّ
the ones that you like, you get married to. So, love must exist between the two.
And this cannot happen without
good acquaintance with the person. You must know the person. You must
know his or her habits and you must know his or her temper. You must know his or her
principles. You just must know the person. You cannot love a person
without knowing that person. So, this calls for a period of
acquaintance, getting to know each other. And then based on that knowledge, you
either love the person or not. And God tells you if you love the person, then
you get married.
God says that if this is the person intended for you, God will put love in
your hearts. And this is in SURA 30 verse 21.
So, the first requirement before ever becoming intimate
is love. You must know each other very well and you must be in love with each
other. And God will help you along if this is the right person. If you don't love
the person, that is not the right person for you.
The second requirement is dowry for the wife.
And we, we understand throughout the Quran, we understand from the Quran that the
purpose of the dowry is security for the woman.
Because in many cases, you are taking a girl from her parents house. Then, she
becomes dependent on the husband. This is the majority of wives in the whole world.
And you can't just throw her out after a year or two,
because she is not the same person. And after what the Quran calls a
formidable oath has been made between the two of you. So, the purpose of the
dowry is security. And this can be
attained by writing a contract and paying the dowry in advance or saying that
if divorce takes place or if the marriage breaks up, then the wife must be given
a certain amount of money that will provide her security. The Quran is very
careful in this respect, even with divorce.
In SURA 2 verse 240 and 241, we see that divorcees must be given
alimony or some kind of security. In SURA 65 the first verse says very
carefully that you can't kick the wife out of your house.
And this provides security for the wife. This is the divorced wife.
And you cannot even fabricate conditions and situations to make them so miserable
that they leave on their own. You must guarantee their housing and
staying with their children. And she will not be the man's wife.
He cannot touch her, but she has to stay in that house.
She must be provided with security of housing, provisions and this is
throughout the Quran. So, this is the purpose of the dowry. These are the two
condition. There must be a sufficient period of time
for the two people to know each other and to satisfy the first requirement of
love before becoming intimate.
What is being done now, what my parents did and what is happening in most Muslim
countries is they actually do official the marriage.
And then, the now husband and wife, they don't touch each other. They do not
become intimate, but this marriage, official marriage gives them a chance
to be together alone, hold hands, go places, know each other. And then after
months or a year or years, the marriage is consummated.
And of course during this period, if it doesn't work out, they break up. They find
somebody else. And she is still a virgin. And she still hasn't lost her chances.
This is how my parents got married, this is how my sister got married.
How long were you... you did the marriage first and then how long was it before consummating the marriage?
You didn't...
There were two years between كتب الكتاب which is the...
Oh, it was an engagement and then two years and then you did official marriage and the consummation
at the same time. So, you had two years of knowing each other. If I was in Egypt, you wouldn't do it....
I'm just kidding.
Oh, you didn't go outside.
You were all... you had a chaperone... OK. I'm satisfied now.
But this is really the way it is done of most marriages in the Muslim world.
Worship in Islam, and all practices in Islam, and all the commandments that God
gave us are based on self discipline and self-control.
I mean, Ramadan is coming up where you're
gonna tell your body you're not gonna eat or drink untill sunset.
This is self....it takes self-discipline and self-control.
Where self discipline and self control is lost,
the human being becomes worse than animals. And there's a specific
reference in the Quran for this in SURA 7 verse 179. God called some
people they are like animals, even worse. I mean, what is happening now in this
country and in Europe is that people meet. They don't even know each
other let's hop in bed. This is worse than animals.
because you can take a female cat or a female dog or a female horse that is not
in heat, not in that proper period and put her in the midst of two hundred
best-looking horny males. Can they touch her?
They will not touch her. They cannot touch her because it is not the proper
time, but with human beings the way it is done now here, it's a lot worse than
animals. They're worse than animals and these are the laws that God
lays down for our happiness. Because
especially for the woman, I mean, she cheapens herself when she acts this way,
for the man, too.
So, the two requirements... I'm repeating again
are that long period of time where people
must know each other and must fall in love before becoming intimate. So, remember love before intimacy,
and the dowry that is to provide security for the wife.
Now, the Quran leaves room for forfeiting the dowry if the wife is independently
wealthy. And being married or unmarried or
divorced or widowed or whatever will not affect her security, then she can forfeit the dowry.
But we have examples of a man who's holding a fantastic position and he's
wealthy and his ex-wife is on welfare. That's not fair.
This is what the Quran... this is what God's laws are supposed to avoid a situation like that.
So, it is to the best for the benefit of the girl to demand her
right when the situation calls for it.
Tooboo Ela Allah. Repent.
ALHAMDU LILLAH, praise be to God. WA ASHHADU AN LA ILAHA ILLA ALLAH WAHDAHU LA SHARIKA LAH.
And we bear witness that there is no god except the One God.
The marriage principles are laid down in the Quran must be known to all of us because
we come across these once in a while. And these are the principles God
prescribed for us to guarantee perfect happiness.
And from my experience, from life experiences and the things I have seen
even if it may look difficult at the beginning,
it is for the best of the couple to follow these prescriptions.
Quite often you read in the newspapers that if I don't acquiesce to him, he's gonna
leave me and find somebody else. Well, let him. He doesn't love you anymore. I mean,
he doesn't love you. That love is not there.
But if the man loves the woman, respects her, then he will...
she will guarantee a husband who loves her. If you follow these steps,
you'll be guaranteed happiness from the physical and spiritual aspect.
Self discipline and self-control,
is easy when the soul is grown and developed and is stronger than the body
which is what the practices of religion are all about, developing your soul, so it'll be
stronger than your body. What you hear about Jimmy Swaggart and Jim Baker,
it shows that they are people whose body
is stronger than their soul. I hear they were preaching against
adultery, and preaching the Word of God supposedly,
and then they are dealing with, with prostitutes.
And for the Muslim, it's.... the Quran provides the solutions to all these problems
that we find in this country, alcohol drugs,
marital problems. Solutions to all the problems are found
in the Quran. We are becoming increasingly
aware of the problems of alcohol and the disasters that come from it. I mean,
wherever you look, there are victims of alcoholism.
But, and please forgive me if I appear to be bragging or anything, but I have
to share with you what the Quran does, what Islam does to us
it's that alcohol is just not in my mind at all. It's out of the question.
And this is the most effective way of dealing with alcohol or drugs. There's
just no way I will be tempted or even think about trying whiskey or gin or
champagne or whatever those things are. It's out of the question. It's just not in my
thinking at all, the same with drugs. And there was a demonstration on the TV
recently, with, what's his name that
had Muslims on the TV talking about drugs? Geraldo Rivera. They had a bunch
of Muslims and they were talking about drugs and they set the example for Harlem or something where drugs are going rampant
and they just, drugs are not
on their mind. Nothing is gonna tempt them to use drugs.
It's the solution to all problems.
And there is a mechanism for it, and the mechanism is that the soul is stronger
than the body, because of all the prayer and the fasting and the things
that God has prescribed for us and constitute gifts from God to us.
And again I will ask you to forgive me if I appear to be bragging, but again I
wanna share with you what Islam does. Now, in my line of work, work with the
United Nations, traveling to different Countries in the world and making a lot
of money. The UN pays the highest salaries in the world
when I was... when I'm with them on assignment.
And I have been to conferences, the American Chemical Society conferences, the
American Association for advancement of science. And in those conferences,
it seems like all the prostitutes of the whole town converge on the hotels where
these conferences are. And I have looked around, and I see
scientists that I respect,
going up or down in the elevator with prostitutes.
And I lose respect for them. And what appears to be bragging is that
I can make a statement here in a KHUTBA in front of you, in a prayer
that I never never fell for prostitutes, for prostitutes, or dealt with a prostitute,
because it is not on my mind. And Jimmy Swaggart cannot make that
statement, or Jim Baker cannot make that statement. Because they lacked... they are using
the wrong techniques. Because of their idolization of Jesus, they
they nullify their work. If they do anything that may cause growth or
development of their soul, it is nullified as the Quran says because of their
idolatry. Therefore, their body is stronger than their souls.
But like with alcohols and drugs, it's just not on my mind.
Now to make that statement absolutely truth, in saying, dealt with
prostitutes, there was one instance where a friend of mine, a colleague,
we went into his room in the hotel in one of the American Chemical Society meetings
to get a book or something. And there was a prostitute passing out in the hall and he
called her in his room and I guess he was bragging or showing off or something,
and bargained with her and I was there witnessing this. This is the extent of my
dealing with prostitutes. So, Islam and the Quran,
just solves all these problems, and lays down the laws and regulations,
and not only teaches self discipline, but it instills it on you and becomes
easy. I mean, there's... it's no problem at all.
God says that you can speak up of God's blessings on you.
And this is the category where we can share with each other
these things, because some people may think it is incredible,
when you go in those conferences and if you make a statement like this to the
people, it's an incredible statement.
And I just... I just couldn't think of a man who under those circumstances did not, for after the
things I have seen, under those circumstances did not fall for prostitutes. The temptation is great.
But for the Muslim, there is no temptation at all. It is zero, doesn't mean a thing.
Aqem Al-Salah.
ALLAH-O AKBAR, ALLAH-O AKBAR, LA ILLAHA ILLA ALLAH.
When you talk about marriage in Islam, you cannot avoid mentioning polygamy
and polygamy is allowed. Throughout history, it was
allowed. In the Bible, it is allowed without
limits. In the Quran, it is allowed with many many conditions and strings
attached to it. But all I can...I need to say is that the prophet Muhammad
provided the perfect example, as far as polygamy is concerned. Muhammad was
married to one wife for 25 years until she died. He had only one wife and
he raised all his children with that one wife.
And after she died, he married women who had many children, who had no support, and
no home. They were widows of his friends who died
in battle or died naturally, and they needed the support. They were old
women. There were only two political marriages;
to the daughter of Abu Bakr and the daughter of Omar, his best friends who
insisted, you know, please you have to marry my daughter.
Because this is a tribal...it's a tribal
tradition. In tribal societies, for different tribes to marry and be connected in marriages important and
this is probably why after the prophet's death, Abu Bakr was elected to be the
Khalifa after the prophet, and Omar followed Abu Bakr. And these are the two
men whose daughters were married to the prophet. But the message, the loud message
here is that Muhammad spent his life, all his young life with one wife and
raised his children and then after that polygamy came into the picture and there
were many special conditions surrounding that. The other subject that I need to
talk about is divorce and I just have to tell you out right that God hates divorce,
throughout the Quran.
Almost invariably children are victimized, even the husband and the wife
are victims in divorce, and this is why it is imperative that we follow these
regulations that God prescribed for us, and avoid divorce at any cause. There's a
verse in Quran that says if you want to substitute a wife in place of another wife...
No, this is not the verse, but there's a verse that says if you dislike your present
wife, you may dislike something where in God has put a lot of good.
The verse that I was mentioning before is if you want to substitute one wife
in place of another, which again actually emphasizes monogamy,
it says do not take anything from the first wife back, and this also brings in
the matter of security for the wife. Because women have been abused
throughout history and God knows that. And God says in SURA 28 verse 5 that
He is for the oppressed and for the rights of the weak. And marriage is a tremendous
contract, is a formidable contract. This is what the Quran calls it.
To take a wife out of her house and take her
into your house, supposedly to live forever.
You know there's tremendous responsibilities associated with that.
So, we pray to God to guide us on His path and to gift... give us the gift of following His commandments.